Hello and welcome back. We are going to be using once again,
大家好 欢迎回来 我们将再一次用到MATLAB
MATLAB to illustrate what we just learned about answer masking, and a few
来举例演示刚刚学到的反锐化掩模
additional operations. So, let's go into that.
以及一些其他的操作 下面 我们来看这个例子
First we're going to read an image, one of the images that come with the matter
首先 我们读入一幅图像 这幅图像来自于MATLAB的包
package. Then we're going to add, salt and pepper
然后向其中加入椒盐噪声
noise. We see here point zero nine meaning, that
这里的0.09表明
about 9% of the pixels in the image, are going to be contaminated by salt, white,
大概9%的像素点会受到噪声影响 盐点是白色
or pepper, meaning black noise. After that, we're going to apply to the
椒点是黑色 这之后 我们将利用
noisy image, medium filtering, and we see that operation here.
中值滤波器处理噪声图像 也就是这一步
And then we're going to load, the original image.
然后载入原始图像
The noisy image, the medium filter result, meaning the denoised image. The
还有噪声图像 和经中值滤波后的去噪图像
difference between these two as one possibility of [INAUDIBLE] masking and
这两个的区别是 一个是原始图像与处理后图像的差
also a stretch histogram. And we're going to see and discuss each
另一个是直方图拉伸后的图像 之后会分别进一步讨论这些图像
one of these more. So let's just first load all the five
首先载入这五幅图像
images and see what happens. I'm going to move them around so we can
看看发生了什么 我把图像移动一下
look at all of them at once. So,
这样就可以同时查看所有的图像
this is once again, we see here first the original image.
第一张是再次看到的原始图像
Then we see the salt and pepper noise. When the background is white, we can see
然后是加入了椒盐噪声的图像 图像的背景是白色时
the black dots, basically the pepper. When the background is dark, when the
可以看到黑色的椒点
background is dark, we can see the white dots, the salt.
当背景是黑色时 可以看到白色的盐点
Here we see the result of applying a three by three medium filter to this
这个是噪声图像经 3×3 的中值滤波器处理后的结果
image. And we see that we managed to clean the
可以看到噪声被成功地消除了
noise. And we managed to clean pretty much the
整个图像变得非常干净
whole image. Of course, we have some blurring not a
当然 图像有一些模糊 但不是很多
lot, but some blurring produced by the medium filter.
其中一些模糊是由中值滤波器产生的
So it's not exactly the original image. It's kind of a blurred version of it.
所以它不是真正意义上的原始图像 只是原始图像的一个模糊版本
Which means that if we take now the difference between these two images,
这意味着如果我们计算这两幅图像的差
we're going to get this, which is mostly the edges the basically sharp boundaries
会得到这幅图像 也就是原始图像中主要的清晰边缘
in this image. This image is a bit too dark and
这幅图像太暗了
therefore what we do as we know we can stretch the histogram and in this case we
因此可以拉伸直方图来改进一下 在这种情况下
just square the pixel values and by that we are stretching the histogram and we
我们通过将像素值平方 来拉伸直方图
see here the results. So here is basically, the difference
这张图像就是最终的结果
between the original, the medium filter of the noise filter, that's that and we
这是原始图像与中值滤波后的噪声图像的差 也就是这张图像
have stretching. Now,
我们还做了直方图的拉伸 现在
observe that we don't see edges, because of the noise.
注意 我们无法看到噪声产生的边缘
Those would be superios edges, won't be real edges in the original image.
那些是虚假边缘 不是原始图像中的真实边缘
And that basically happens because we have applied a medium filter before
这是因为在做差之前 利用了中值滤波器做处理
producing these difference. And that's actually great, because the
这个真的很不错 因为
medium filter manages to get rid of the noise.
中值滤波器能成功消除噪声
And therefore managed to get rid of the possibility of having superious edges.
因此成功消除了产生虚假边缘的可能性
So in this example, we see a lot of the things that we have learned.
在这个例子中 我们重温了很多之前学过知识
We see salt and pepper noise, result of medium filter.
复习了椒盐噪声 实践了中值滤波器
The difference producing the most important edges and an histogram
图像之间做差能生成最关键的边缘
stretching to be able to observe those edges in a much nicer way.
直方图的拉伸能够让我们更好地观察这些边缘
Thank you very much, and see you in the next video.
非常感谢大家 我们下个视频再见 // 果壳教育无边界字幕组 | luoyetx | 林小七Lynn | wugui